<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Infuse</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/</link><description>Recent content on Infuse</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>ar</language><atom:link href="https://infuse.quest/ar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Infuse</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/about/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Infrastructure Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While this learning path focuses on web application security, web applications run on top of numerous pieces of software infrastructure. Any vulnerability in the application’s underlying infrastructure will compromise the application. Understanding some infrastructure security is therefore part of understanding application security.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When inspecting a web application either for purposes of vulnerability assessment, security monitoring, or to investigate a compromise, the practitioner must understand the underlying stack of technology which provides the necessary environment for the application to run while looking for vulnerabilities in that stack.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interpersonal skills for detecting malware</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before you start analyzing any malware, you need to set up a safe environment to do so. Definitionally, malware does bad things to the systems it runs on. You do not want to run it on your primary system. Additionally, you likely will want to prevent the malware from actually making connections to the threat actor’s C&amp;amp;C (command and control) servers. Both of these mean that you should set up a virtual machine to use when performing malware analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Phishing messages are usually tied to malicious infrastructure that either seeks to capture login credentials and use them to access an organization’s or individual&amp;rsquo;s systems, or otherwise seeks to deliver a socially-engineered compromise such as a browser or device exploit. They are one of the most common techniques used by malicious actors who aim to compromise NGOs. Very often, an NGO that receives such a message might find it difficult to tell with certainty whether it was suspicious, much less what the identity and goal of the attacker were. Checking with the presumed sender through another channel might be the easiest way to verify whether a message was legitimate. If the sender cannot be contacted or if the message was not legitimate, it might be important to analyze it in more depth. This could allow us to stop such attacks before they compromise an NGO’s systems, prevent them from doing so in the future, and alert others within the community to such attackers and their tactics, techniques, and procedures (TTPs). The results of such investigations are then often shared, either through formal reports or networks, or informal discussions between NGO security professionals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This learning path covers intermediate-level knowledge and skills needed to detect and identify malware either from a given sample, or actively operating on a device on a variety of device platforms. The distinction between malware and software can be very subtle, and a detailed analysis of processes and binaries to ultimately determine what is malware sometimes requires advanced-level expertise. However, the skills covered here will give you a start in detection efforts. This learning path covers:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/3/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/3/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This learning path will prepare you to start on the journey of analyzing malware. Note that this is one of the hardest areas of security to master, but incremental progress will give results. The general goal of malware analysis is to characterize new malware, both brand new malware and variants of existing ones. The desired end result is a characterization of the capabilities of the malware, a guess at what threat actor(s) is using it, and a set of IoCs (indicators of compromise) that will allow others to detect the malware.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are many ways in which adversaries could try to attack websites, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Denial of expression: website takedown, website defacement, denial of service&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Accessing sensitive data: exploiting access controls or other vulnerabilities to access information for instance in application databases, private files or systems, private inboxes or members’ areas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implanting malware ( ‘watering hole’ attacks): using access to a website to place malicious or misleading code for the purpose of achieving objectives on visitor devices&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lateral movement (compromising other systems): gaining access to whole servers, cloud infrastructure, or office or home infrastructure&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Surveillance of visitors: obtaining information on IPs or identities of visitors to a website or users of a web application&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supply chain compromise: compromising distribution services for software, building processes of software, or for component libraries of software in order to achieve malicious objectives on users of the targeted software&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Impersonation of websites: for purposes of phishing, muddying of reputation, and malware/spyware distribution&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Traffic injection (downgrading attacks): exploiting infrastructure or communications configuration weaknesses for the purpose of inserting malicious content into otherwise good traffic&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Web application security is a deep domain of technical knowledge with many areas of specialization. This learning path will provide you with a general understanding of web application vulnerabilities and how some of the more common ones work. It should help you understand the types of vulnerabilities that commonly exist in web applications, capabilities that these vulnerabilities give to attackers, and how, in general, to eliminate or mitigate these vulnerabilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Web applications are critical infrastructure used by media organizations and civil society to disseminate free flow of information as well as to provide functionalities to their stakeholders. Adversaries attack these web applications for various purposes, including shutting down the free flow of information, reputational damage, access to private systems, theft of sensitive information, surveillance, and device compromise. By proactively identifying vulnerabilities in web applications used by your clients and partners, you can head off potential compromises before they occur.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Websites are critical infrastructure used by media organizations and civil society to disseminate free flow of information as well as to provide functionalities to their stakeholders. Adversaries attack these web applications for various purposes, including shutting down the free flow of information, reputational damage, access to private systems, theft of sensitive information, surveillance, and device compromise. By preparing effectively for these sorts of attacks, you can reduce their impact, or in some cases prevent them entirely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setting up a malware analysis environment</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/3/module-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/3/module-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before you start analyzing any malware, you need to set up a safe environment to do so. Definitionally, malware does bad things to the systems it runs on. You do not want to run it on your primary system. Additionally, you likely will want to prevent the malware from actually making connections to the threat actor’s C&amp;amp;C (command and control) servers. Both of these mean that you should set up a virtual machine to use when performing malware analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setup</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Effectively testing web applications for security vulnerabilities requires specialized tools, which this subtopic looks at.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The most important of these tools is an intercepting proxy server, which will allow you to directly interact with HTTP data as it flows back and forth between your browser and the target web server. This will let you observe what data is being exchanged and manipulate it without the interference of your browser or any client-side controls that are in place.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Triage - Deciding when to investigate</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you receive or are forwarded a suspicious message, conduct initial triage in order to determine if it is indeed malicious, to figure out the best rapid response for the targeted recipient(s) if it is, and to determine if further investigation is needed. For most messages, it’s enough to conduct basic heuristics to separate untargeted from targeted threats and to identify harm-reducing actions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, the practitioner should be able to differentiate between legitimate emails, untargeted spam or phishing emails, and targeted ones based on several heuristic indicators.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Website Hardening</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/module-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/module-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are a number of steps that can be taken to a website as a whole to make it more resilient to attack. These typically require less effort than going through the site page-by-page and can be quite impactful, so generally it’s a good idea to go through these actions first.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, the practitioner should be able to do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use development and maintenance processes that ensure that their site can be re-created if the production hosting servers are unavailable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use CDNs (content delivery networks) to protect their website from DoS attacks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use static site generators to make their site more resistant to DoS and hacking&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use configuration hardeners and WAFs to make their site more resistant to hacking&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This sub-skill covers fundamental, site-wide activities that should be performed on almost any site that wishes to be protected against attacks. While every action may not apply to every site, some apply to all sites, and all apply to some.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Basic file analysis</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/3/module-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/3/module-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once you have a piece of malware on your analysis VM, the next step is to figure out what’s in it. A piece of malware may use multiple files; in this case you would use the techniques in this section for each file. There are a few different ways to get an idea of what kind of file you’re dealing with. Note that some malware is tricky about this, hiding malicious content in innocuous files or making files that are several valid types at once (a classic example being the GIFAR, which is a file that is both a valid image and also a valid Java applet). Because of this, when evaluating malware files, we need to perform a deeper analysis of file types and contents. Beyond basic file extensions, we’ll examine file headers and signatures, as well as string contents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Validation</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A common class of web application vulnerabilities relates to the way the app processes data supplied by users of the site. This class of vulnerabilities is commonly used by attackers to completely take over target websites, and often can be discovered via automated techniques. Understanding the mechanisms for data validation vulnerabilities is also extremely useful for demystifying complex security topics.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Validation</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One way or another, every web application accepts and processes untrusted input. This input usually comes from end users and their browsers but may also come from other websites or backend systems. Depending on where this information flows, the processing of the data may have undesirable effects on the website or its users.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners will be able to find ways that the format or structure of the data sent to a website may expose and exploit vulnerabilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interpersonal Skills for Malicious Infrastructure/Phishing Response</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In almost every intervention or support case, practitioners will be working directly with persons affected by an attack or attempted attack. This can often be a stressful and anxiety-inducing experience for targeted persons, and every practitioner should know how to mitigate those pressures.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners will be able to support those who might have received or clicked on malicious emails or links in a responsible way, embodying empathy and focusing on harm reduction informed by the targeted person’s own threat model.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OPSEC prerequisites for detecting malware</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This subtopic will allow the practitioner to ensure the security of the process and the individuals involved and implement a security policy within the computing environment the practitioner uses for malware detection.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, the practitioner should be able to ensure the confidentiality and integrity of data, which includes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Encryption during storage and transfer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Doing checksums after data acquisitions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Not using devices suspected of being compromised&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using air-gapped environments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ensuring security of the devices and servers used in the process&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Threat modeling and risk assessment&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Conducting backups and disk imaging&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Operational security for detecting malware can be divided into concerns related to specific scenarios:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Website Logging for Security</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/module-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/module-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Any website that’s exposed to the internet is under constant attack. At the very least, it’s being deluged by undirected attacks by hordes of robots operated by criminal actors. More concerning are targeted attacks; even unskilled attackers, given perseverance and luck, can find vulnerabilities in a website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ideally, the website owner should be able to be aware of the threats they are facing. Site owners especially will want to know if an attacker is close to finding, or has recently found, a vulnerability in their site. Finally, if a vulnerability is exploited, site owners will want to know where the vulnerability is, and for how long it’s been exploited. Website logs can support all of these desires.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>كيف يعمل</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/how/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/how/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Authentication</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In any website that has user logins, it’s important that the site protects user accounts from unauthorized access, and also that the account credentials themselves are protected. This subtopic outlines the most common areas of authentication where web application flaws appear.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Understand common types of authentication vulnerabilities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understand the potential impacts of those types of vulnerabilities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understand the mechanisms by which those vulnerabilities work&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understand, in broad strokes, how those vulnerabilities can be prevented&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Authentication is the process by which a user of a system proves that they are who they claim they are. It is the foundation upon which access control is built. Typically, a user will supply a piece of information that identifies them (username, email address, phone number, etc.) and a piece of secret information that validates that identity (commonly a password or passphrase, though alternative or additional methods such as a security keys, WebAuthn, and Passkeys are gaining popularity). This subtopic will cover a few vulnerability classes that are common and high-impact in web applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Authentication and Authorization</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Many web apps will only allow particular users to view certain pieces of content and require them to log in or prove their identity in other ways. Adversaries who want to access sensitive data will often try to bypass those restrictions and attempt to view information they are not allowed to see. This subtopic looks into the idea of authentication and authorization, and possible vulnerabilities therein.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners will be able to find weaknesses in web applications that allow them to partially or completely bypass those applications’ authentication systems or abuse authentication to disclose information about a site’s users.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Denial of Service Incident Response</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/module-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/module-3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If a website comes under a sustained denial of service attack, it may be vital to act quickly to get the site back up and running. This subtopic describes some practices to allow site owners to recover from a DoS attack.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, the practitioner should be able to do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Determine what sort of DoS attack a website is under&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mitigate or neutralize an attack in process&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For some sites (e.g., gambling sites), even a brief DoS can be an existential threat to the site’s survival. Attackers are typically financially motivated, and will use DoS as an extortion threat. For civil society focused sites, the threat model is typically quite different. Attacks are typically controlled by political rivals (often nation-state actors or those linked to or supported by them), and fall into two categories:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How malware works and different types of malware</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In order to start working with malware, we first need to learn about its different types. Viruses, spyware, backdoors, ransomware, and adware behave differently and are inspired by different motivations. This knowledge will help the protector to classify the type of malware detected.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, the practitioner should be able to do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Differentiate between various types of malware&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understand what malware can do&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understand how malware infections begin&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Explain what indicators of compromise are&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In general, malware is any software that is used to do unauthorized things on a user’s computer or mobile device. Wikipedia has a good &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malware" target="_blank" >introduction to malware in general.&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Operational Security - Safe Handling of links and infrastructure</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As you go about investigating malicious phishing emails, attachments, websites, and other infrastructure, you will need to take some proactive steps to make sure that you keep yourself and the people you support safe. You will also need to know what to advise the recipient of the messages whenever they are faced with such incidents, and how they can safely report it to you for handling without compromising themselves.
Be sure to study this skill and, if necessary, set up a safe environment before interacting with suspected malicious emails or web pages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sandboxes and dynamic analysis</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/3/module-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/3/module-3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dynamic analysis is the process of running a piece of malware and observing what it does. The easiest way of doing dynamic analysis is by running a piece of software in a sandbox. A sandbox is a safe, isolated environment which opens a potentially malicious file, URL, or program and generates a huge amount of data on it. This subtopic looks at sandbox analysis, what it can and cannot do, and how to do it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>المساهمة</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/contribute/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/contribute/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Application Logic and Related Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There exist other types of vulnerabilities not covered in the above subtopics which could nonetheless be used to damage or gain unauthorized entry into a web app. We look at several of those below. This is the last subtopic which outlines vulnerability classes: once you’ve learned about all of them, you can move on to the next topics, which look into scanning your web apps for potential vulnerabilities and ensuring that they do not have any serious security holes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Authorization</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In any website that has users with different levels of capabilities (e.g. viewers vs editors) or that holds confidential information for users, it’s important that the site protects these features and/or this data from people who don’t have permission to use these features and/or interact with this data.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Understand common types of authorization vulnerabilities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understand the potential impacts of those types of vulnerabilities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understand the mechanisms by which those vulnerabilities work&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understand, in broad strokes, how those vulnerabilities can be prevented&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="foundation-knowledge">Foundation Knowledge&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Authorization is the process of making sure that a user of a system has permission to perform an action or create/read/edit/delete a piece of data in that system, and preventing these actions if the user doesn’t have permission. Generally, these are the simplest types of security controls to implement, and the simplest type of vulnerability to find. However, even though they are conceptually simple, both securing and breaking the controls are generally very tedious and error-prone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Community</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/community/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/community/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hacking Incident Response</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/module-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/module-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If a website is hacked, understanding the actions and methods of the attacker is vital. At the very least, the site owners need to identify how the site was initially compromised so that they can fix any vulnerabilities that enabled that. It may also be important to know what data the attackers may have accessed or modified. This subtopic describes some practices to help investigate and recover from a website hacking incident.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Initial steps and checks for detecting malware</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There is a device of unknown security status and the owner wants to investigate the possibility of infection or previous compromise. Perhaps you have been handed this device physically, or perhaps you will support the client remotely. Use different off-the-shelf or built-in first party scanning tools as well as integrity checks to identify, analyze, and search for Indicators of compromise (IoC) to identify a breach, or a given suspicious malware.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Passive Investigation - Analyze URLs, hostnames, and IP addresses</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A practitioner can use the skills outlined in this subtopic to &lt;strong>begin a passive investigation against servers on the internet&lt;/strong>. A passive investigation is one that does not load any websites, but only looks up publicly available data on them. As such, the attacker will not be alerted that their website received additional visits, which could tip them off that an investigation is taking place. By evaluating domain and IP info, an investigator can work towards **generating rich technical information about the attack **useful for community education, threat information sharing, discovery of associated attacker infrastructure, and for placing attacks in context of broader attack patterns.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Static analysis</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/3/module-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/3/module-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Static analysis is the process of disassembling a binary file in order to understand what’s inside it. It’s quite labor-intensive and requires software engineering knowledge. For this reason, most analysts will prefer to do dynamic analysis (which we focus on in Subtopic 3) instead. There are several reasons you might want to do static analysis, including when dynamic analysis isn’t yielding good results or if you do not want a potential adversary to know that you are in possession of and analyzing the file.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/badge-descriptions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/badge-descriptions/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Application Logic</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-5/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In any interactive website that puts constraints on the types of actions that users can perform, it’s important that the site properly enforces those constraints to prevent unintended (and potentially) damaging actions by malicious users.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Understand the concept of application logic vulnerabilities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Identify and understand common subclasses of application logic vulnerabilities, including:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Client-side controls&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lack of rate limiting/multiple submissions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rounding inconsistencies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Skipping process steps&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cross-site request forgery&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Application logic vulnerabilities (frequently called business logic vulnerabilities) are a loosely assembled class of vulnerabilities that relate to the processes that the application itself performs, as opposed to underlying vulnerabilities in the technologies that the application uses. If this definition is confusing to you, you’re in good company. What constitutes a business logic vulnerability vs some other class is hotly contested. Infuse takes the position that the actual definition doesn’t matter that much, and that expediency is more important than precise definitions. We encourage you to maintain a focus on the vulnerabilities themselves, develop a view of vulnerability classes that makes sense to you, and maintain flexibility in taxonomy when discussing vulnerabilities with others.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Creating and sharing IoCs</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/3/module-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/3/module-5/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once you have analyzed a piece of malware, you can help the community (and also yourself and the rest of the world) by sharing your findings. Novel malware is reasonably rare, and once used, it tends to be re-used extensively. By sharing your findings, you can help everyone in several ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If a member of the community has been targeted by a threat actor, it’s quite possible that the threat actor is targeting other members of the community. By sharing your findings, you can help raise awareness and hopefully help digital defenders prevent or mitigate other attacks.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Analyzing a novel piece of malware is a significant achievement. You should be proud of it and also be rewarded for your efforts. By sharing your process and findings, you are more likely to be recognized for your expertise, increasing your opportunities for interesting work and collaboration in the field.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finally, by creating and sharing IoCs, you can help automatic detection of the malware in question. If makers of detection and prevention software integrate those IoCs into their databases, that renders the malware significantly less useful to threat actors and enhances the security of people all over the world.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Finding Web Application Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-5/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once you have learned about different types of vulnerabilities, it&amp;rsquo;s time to look for them in the web applications you are testing! To start with and get some initial practice, you will test a deliberately vulnerable web application.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners will be able to find vulnerabilities in a real website, as opposed to understanding individual vulnerabilities in isolation.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Having completed the previous subtopics, you should have a good understanding of individual vulnerabilities. While this might be enough to guide you in fixing vulnerabilities or perform forensics in a web application breach, it is not enough if you wish to find those vulnerabilities in a web application. While the previous labs were focused puzzles challenging you to activate a vulnerability in a single input, in a real web application most inputs will not be vulnerable to anything. Your challenge will be to find those rare inputs that are vulnerable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Forensic methods on live Windows and macOS systems</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-5/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Direct inspection of a device can be necessary to understand what is happening on it and to identify suspicious processes, artifacts, or traffic. Go beyond scanning tools by using methods to take a deeper look at what is happening on a device.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Understand ways of inspecting running processes and methods to sort out potentially suspicious processes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understand common persistence mechanisms and ways of checking for them&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Inspect network traffic for suspicious communications&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Forensic methods require more knowledge about the internal operations of an operating system as well as developing an instinct for what is normal vs abnormal findings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Passive Investigation - Analyze email headers</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-5/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There is far more to emails than meets the eye. The subtopic will teach you how to &lt;strong>analyze the extensive metadata&lt;/strong> which documents an email’s origin, the servers it traveled through, information about possible spam checks, and much more. This metadata can form a crucial part of any in-depth investigation into potentially malicious emails.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Use this skill after or alongside the &lt;a href="#subtopic-4-passive-investigation-analyze-urls-hostnames-and-ip-addresses" >Triage&lt;/a> subtopic within this learning path. Some of these skills may be necessary as part of the triage process in order to decide if a message is suspicious.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Active Investigation - Analyze malicious emails</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-6/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This module will teach you how to &lt;strong>interpret and understand malicious emails&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>find the infrastructure that they link to&lt;/strong>. Whether they be pure social engineering, phishing, or malware delivery, malicious emails can be quite complex. While the immediate goal of this skill is to identify attacker infrastructure, these advanced skills of reversing complex emails are also good preparation for understanding attacker campaigns, and they are a good introduction to analyzing more complicated malware. Some of those techniques can also &lt;strong>help you analyze suspicious messages sent through other mediums, such as WhatsApp&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Detecting malware through traffic analysis</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-6/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Most malware will make some sort of network connection, be it to connect to a command and control server for further instructions or exfiltrate data from a computer. While various tactics can be used by malware to avoid being detected by antivirus scanners, in many cases an analyst with access to all network traffic from the device can spot those suspicious network connections and analyze them to look for signs of malicious activity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interpersonal Skills for Web Application Security</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-6/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When interacting with individuals and organizations who operate web applications, self-awareness is necessary to check the nature of the digital protector relationship, provide useful and not fear-mongering advice or services. It is critical to frame your technical work within a sound risk assessment of the reality of the web application and its users.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Self reflect on the digital protector relationship with a client within web application assessment work and reporting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Simplify and filter findings and explain them in a way which makes sense to the needs and threat models of the organization and its stakeholders&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Maintain an awareness of the limits of your own knowledge and ability&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Communicate in a non fear-mongering way about vulnerabilities and weaknesses&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Conduct a broader risk analysis of a web application based on the political, social, economic, and technical realities which surround it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Your work in web application security assessment must remain contextualized within the frame of the organization which operates or hosts the application, the people who utilize it (and of their devices), the interpersonal relationships you have with these people, the nature of the web application itself, the data stored or processed on it, the legal realities which prevail over the application, and a solid risk assessment of all these elements. Let’s unpack these elements and consider a self-critique of your role as a digital protector.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Refining Your Web Application Testing Process</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-6/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Subtopic 5 is a prerequisite for this one, and learners are strongly encouraged to thoroughly read it before proceeding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re like most people, you struggled with the last practice. It probably took you a long time, and you probably missed a bunch of vulnerabilities. Don’t be dispirited! Before you started this, you would’ve found far fewer in far more time. It may not feel great, but it’s very difficult to transition from learning about vulnerabilities in isolation to finding them in an open-ended environment. So, struggling and not being super-successful is part of the process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Active Investigation - Analyze malicious webpages</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-7/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Phishing emails are usually just the first step in an attack. Most try to get the targeted person to visit a web page with a specific attack objective. This skill module will teach you to &lt;strong>look at attacker-controlled websites to understand their actions&lt;/strong> and potentially &lt;strong>uncover further attacker-controlled infrastructure&lt;/strong> or attack vectors used in the attacks. Note that websites can be extremely complicated, with behavior ranging from simple credential-stealing impersonation pages to complex attacks against the web browser or browsing device itself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automatic Vulnerability Discovery</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-7/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This learning path has focused on manual discovery of vulnerabilities in web applications. This skill is vital for understanding the vulnerabilities and also gives you the tools to find them on any site. However, there are numerous tools that can help with vulnerability discovery and exploitation in web applications. These tools have both advantages and disadvantages and are best used in conjunction with manual testing. This subtopic reviews a number of freely available tools and how to use them effectively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Detecting malware through image acquisition (iOS, Android)</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-7/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The first step in detecting malware on a device is to collect data from the device itself for analysis. Ideally the data will be retrieved from the device to a safe space with minimal disruption to the device itself. More advanced malware may attempt to detect forensic activity and delete itself to hamper detection and analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Documenting Findings</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-8/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There can be several reasons why civil society organizations do not report or share their findings. They might lack the time to do so, they might be concerned about sharing malware samples or indicators of compromise, or they might simply lack the expertise on how to responsibly document the findings of a malware investigation. This subtopic addresses the last point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prior to completing this subtopic, make sure that you’ve thoroughly read through and understood the two writeups (by Amnesty/HRW and by Bellingcat) outlined in Subtopic 7.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Next Steps</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-8/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At this point, you should be able to perform professional-quality security assessments of websites. However, you still have a lot to learn in terms of managing and refining the work of testing and also in terms of more obscure and advanced testing techniques. This subtopic covers some paths you can take to continue to practice and build your skills.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners should know how they can continue to practice and develop their web application security assessment skills.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sample-based detection and determination</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-8/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You have a sample of a file and need to determine if it is malicious. This may have been sent to the target by email, social media, or instant messenger, or transferred over removable media or otherwise. The file itself may be a binary, a compressed archive, a captured web page, or other file formats. The primary objective is to determine whether the file is malicious. In addition, you may be able to determine some additional useful characterizing information about the file, however for more guidance see the &lt;a href="https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/3/" >Malware Analysis Learning Path&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Malicious document analysis</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-9/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While many people know to be suspicious of executable binary files, office document formats such as PDF, DOC, DOCX, XLSX, and ODT, which are used on a daily basis, are unfortunately known to be weaponized with malicious dynamic content or application exploits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This subtopic teaches learners how they can triage and analyze potentially malicious documents.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Response - Infrastructure takedown</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-9/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the previous sub-topics, we looked at how you can identify infrastructure that serves malicious content, be it spam, malware, or phishing. Once you have successfully done so, it’s time to warn others about it. In this subtopic, we cover &lt;strong>abuse-reporting and other safe browsing and sinkhole mechanisms&lt;/strong>. This includes contacting the infrastructure provider to report malicious infrastructure so that it can be taken down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pair this effort with broader incident response activities including threat sharing and reaching out to communities which may have also been targeted by the attacks originating from the same infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Capture-the-flag exercise</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/1/module-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>We have also designed a capture-the-flag exercise in which learners can analyze a phishing email and the infrastructure it links to. The exercise can be used as an additional practice or skill verification exercise, and can be found below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You are sitting in the bustling Press newsroom where you are working as an IT admin, sitting totally focused on your duties surrounded by glowing monitors. Your colleague Alia from Accounting rushes over with a concerned look on their face, who lets you know they forwarded an email claiming to be from PayPal which urges them to take immediate action due to suspicious account activity. The Press organization relies on PayPal for processing subscription payments. Your interest is instantly piqued as you recognize the potential of a malicious attack, and you get started on an investigation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Discovering where the malware came from</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-10/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>No malware spontaneously appears on a targeted person’s device. It always comes from somewhere. Sometimes, that somewhere is obvious: the targeted person realizes that the link they clicked on was malicious. In other cases, the infection vector may be less clear. Learning where the infection came from can be important for managing future risk. If the initial infection source was untargeted, the victim may have just been the victim of a criminal gang with no goals other than making money. On the other hand, if the initial infection came from a sophisticated targeted social engineering attack, they are likely to face continuing future attacks from the same threat actor.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Clean-up, after-care, post-incident risk management, and information sharing</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-11/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If malware or malicious traffic is found on a targeted person’s device, we need to either provide remedial after-care or targeted recommendations to allow a client to determine appropriate next steps.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Determine the appropriate clean-up method for the type of malware or indicator of compromise discovered&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Carry out or guide on remedial clean-up steps, including removal of persistence mechanisms, malware removal tools, reboots, factory resets&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Identify situations in which clean-up may not be possible and further advice or action may be necessary&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Document and share findings&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="re-enabling-operating-system-security-features">Re-enabling operating system security features&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Earlier in this learning path we mentioned &lt;a href="https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/2/module-4/#triagechecklists-to-check-for-missing-protections" >some built-in operating system protections&lt;/a>. If malware was able to run on a targeted person’s system just because some of those protections were disabled, then re-enabling them may help prevent malware from executing or doing any further damage. Some less sophisticated pieces of malware could therefore stop running or even be removed just by going into operating system settings and re-enabling protections. In case you are unable to re-enable these protections or if they are disabled again after some time, this is an indication that the malicious process is preventing the proper functioning of the operating system and further clean-up work or factory reset are required. Do note that in some instances you may find instances that OS protections have been disabled in order to install pirated software, which the user may not immediately communicate to you. It is helpful to know this scenario and to guide the client in risk-management decisions and find safer alternatives which preserve operating system integrity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>التسجيل</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/signup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/signup/</guid><description/></item><item><title>الملف الشخصي</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/profile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/profile/</guid><description/></item><item><title>بحث</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/search/</guid><description/></item><item><title>تسجيل الدخول</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/login/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/login/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>