<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fortalecimiento de Aplicación Web, Análisis Forense y Respuesta a Incidentes on Infuse</title><link>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/6/</link><description>Recent content in Fortalecimiento de Aplicación Web, Análisis Forense y Respuesta a Incidentes on Infuse</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>es</language><atom:link href="https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fortificación del Sitio Web</title><link>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/6/module-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/6/module-1/</guid><description>Caso de Uso Hay una serie de pasos que se pueden seguir en un sitio web en su conjunto para hacerlo más resistente a los ataques. Por lo general, requieren menos esfuerzo que revisar el sitio página por página y pueden tener un gran impacto, por lo que, en general, es una buena idea realizar estas acciones primero.
Objetivos Después de completar este subtema, el profesional debe ser capaz de realizar lo siguiente:</description></item><item><title>Introducción</title><link>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/6/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/6/introduction/</guid><description>Colaboradores
Ninoslava Bogdanović
Michał &amp;ldquo;czesiek&amp;rdquo; Czyżewski https://czesiek.net
Yana Ghahramanyan
Descripción general Los sitios web son una infraestructura crítica utilizada por las organizaciones de medios y la sociedad civil para difundir información libremente, así como para proporcionar funcionalidades a sus partes interesadas. Los adversarios atacan estas aplicaciones web con diversos fines, incluido el cierre del libre flujo de información, daños a la reputación, acceso a sistemas privados, robo de información confidencial, vigilancia y vulneración de dispositivos.</description></item><item><title>Website Logging for Security</title><link>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/6/module-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/6/module-2/</guid><description>Use Case Any website that’s exposed to the internet is under constant attack. At the very least, it’s being deluged by undirected attacks by hordes of robots operated by criminal actors. More concerning are targeted attacks; even unskilled attackers, given perseverance and luck, can find vulnerabilities in a website.
Ideally, the website owner should be able to be aware of the threats they are facing. Site owners especially will want to know if an attacker is close to finding, or has recently found, a vulnerability in their site.</description></item><item><title>Denial of Service Incident Response</title><link>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/6/module-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/6/module-3/</guid><description>Use Case If a website comes under a sustained denial of service attack, it may be vital to act quickly to get the site back up and running. This Learning Path describes some practices to allow site owners to recover from a DoS attack.
Objectives After completing this subtopic, the practitioner should be able to do the following:
Determine what sort of DoS attack a website is under Mitigate or neutralize an attack in process For some sites (e.</description></item><item><title>Hacking Incident Response</title><link>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/6/module-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/6/module-4/</guid><description>Use Case If a website is hacked, understanding the actions and methods of the attacker is vital. At the very least, the site owners need to identify how the site was initially compromised so that they can fix any vulnerabilities that enabled that. It may also be important to know what data the attackers may have accessed or modified. This learning path describes some practices to help investigate and recover from a website hacking incident.</description></item></channel></rss>