<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web Application Security Assessment on Infuse</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/</link><description>Recent content in Web Application Security Assessment on Infuse</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>ar</language><atom:link href="https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Web applications are critical infrastructure used by media organizations and civil society to disseminate free flow of information as well as to provide functionalities to their stakeholders. Adversaries attack these web applications for various purposes, including shutting down the free flow of information, reputational damage, access to private systems, theft of sensitive information, surveillance, and device compromise. By proactively identifying vulnerabilities in web applications used by your clients and partners, you can head off potential compromises before they occur.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setup</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Effectively testing web applications for security vulnerabilities requires specialized tools, which this subtopic looks at.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The most important of these tools is an intercepting proxy server, which will allow you to directly interact with HTTP data as it flows back and forth between your browser and the target web server. This will let you observe what data is being exchanged and manipulate it without the interference of your browser or any client-side controls that are in place.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Validation</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One way or another, every web application accepts and processes untrusted input. This input usually comes from end users and their browsers but may also come from other websites or backend systems. Depending on where this information flows, the processing of the data may have undesirable effects on the website or its users.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners will be able to find ways that the format or structure of the data sent to a website may expose and exploit vulnerabilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Authentication and Authorization</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Many web apps will only allow particular users to view certain pieces of content and require them to log in or prove their identity in other ways. Adversaries who want to access sensitive data will often try to bypass those restrictions and attempt to view information they are not allowed to see. This subtopic looks into the idea of authentication and authorization, and possible vulnerabilities therein.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners will be able to find weaknesses in web applications that allow them to partially or completely bypass those applications’ authentication systems or abuse authentication to disclose information about a site’s users.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Application Logic and Related Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There exist other types of vulnerabilities not covered in the above subtopics which could nonetheless be used to damage or gain unauthorized entry into a web app. We look at several of those below. This is the last subtopic which outlines vulnerability classes: once you’ve learned about all of them, you can move on to the next topics, which look into scanning your web apps for potential vulnerabilities and ensuring that they do not have any serious security holes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Finding Web Application Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-5/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once you have learned about different types of vulnerabilities, it&amp;rsquo;s time to look for them in the web applications you are testing! To start with and get some initial practice, you will test a deliberately vulnerable web application.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners will be able to find vulnerabilities in a real website, as opposed to understanding individual vulnerabilities in isolation.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Having completed the previous subtopics, you should have a good understanding of individual vulnerabilities. While this might be enough to guide you in fixing vulnerabilities or perform forensics in a web application breach, it is not enough if you wish to find those vulnerabilities in a web application. While the previous labs were focused puzzles challenging you to activate a vulnerability in a single input, in a real web application most inputs will not be vulnerable to anything. Your challenge will be to find those rare inputs that are vulnerable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Refining Your Web Application Testing Process</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-6/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Subtopic 5 is a prerequisite for this one, and learners are strongly encouraged to thoroughly read it before proceeding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you’re like most people, you struggled with the last practice. It probably took you a long time, and you probably missed a bunch of vulnerabilities. Don’t be dispirited! Before you started this, you would’ve found far fewer in far more time. It may not feel great, but it’s very difficult to transition from learning about vulnerabilities in isolation to finding them in an open-ended environment. So, struggling and not being super-successful is part of the process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automatic Vulnerability Discovery</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-7/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This learning path has focused on manual discovery of vulnerabilities in web applications. This skill is vital for understanding the vulnerabilities and also gives you the tools to find them on any site. However, there are numerous tools that can help with vulnerability discovery and exploitation in web applications. These tools have both advantages and disadvantages and are best used in conjunction with manual testing. This subtopic reviews a number of freely available tools and how to use them effectively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Next Steps</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/5/module-8/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At this point, you should be able to perform professional-quality security assessments of websites. However, you still have a lot to learn in terms of managing and refining the work of testing and also in terms of more obscure and advanced testing techniques. This subtopic covers some paths you can take to continue to practice and build your skills.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners should know how they can continue to practice and develop their web application security assessment skills.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>