<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Detecting, Investigating and Tracking Malicious Infrastructure on Infuse</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/</link><description>Recent content in Detecting, Investigating and Tracking Malicious Infrastructure on Infuse</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Phishing messages are usually tied to malicious infrastructure that either seeks to capture login credentials and use them to access an organization’s or individual&amp;rsquo;s systems, or otherwise seeks to deliver a socially-engineered compromise such as a browser or device exploit. They are one of the most common techniques used by malicious actors who aim to compromise NGOs. Very often, an NGO that receives such a message might find it difficult to tell with certainty whether it was suspicious, much less what the identity and goal of the attacker were. Checking with the presumed sender through another channel might be the easiest way to verify whether a message was legitimate. If the sender cannot be contacted or if the message was not legitimate, it might be important to analyze it in more depth. This could allow us to stop such attacks before they compromise an NGO’s systems, prevent them from doing so in the future, and alert others within the community to such attackers and their tactics, techniques, and procedures (TTPs). The results of such investigations are then often shared, either through formal reports or networks, or informal discussions between NGO security professionals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Triage - Deciding when to investigate</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When you receive or are forwarded a suspicious message, conduct initial triage in order to determine if it is indeed malicious, to figure out the best rapid response for the targeted recipient(s) if it is, and to determine if further investigation is needed. For most messages, it’s enough to conduct basic heuristics to separate untargeted from targeted threats and to identify harm-reducing actions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, the practitioner should be able to differentiate between legitimate emails, untargeted spam or phishing emails, and targeted ones based on several heuristic indicators.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interpersonal Skills for Malicious Infrastructure/Phishing Response</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In almost every intervention or support case, practitioners will be working directly with persons affected by an attack or attempted attack. This can often be a stressful and anxiety-inducing experience for targeted persons, and every practitioner should know how to mitigate those pressures.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners will be able to support those who might have received or clicked on malicious emails or links in a responsible way, embodying empathy and focusing on harm reduction informed by the targeted person’s own threat model.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Operational Security - Safe Handling of links and infrastructure</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As you go about investigating malicious phishing emails, attachments, websites, and other infrastructure, you will need to take some proactive steps to make sure that you keep yourself and the people you support safe. You will also need to know what to advise the recipient of the messages whenever they are faced with such incidents, and how they can safely report it to you for handling without compromising themselves.
Be sure to study this skill and, if necessary, set up a safe environment before interacting with suspected malicious emails or web pages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Passive Investigation - Analyze URLs, hostnames, and IP addresses</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A practitioner can use the skills outlined in this subtopic to &lt;strong>begin a passive investigation against servers on the internet&lt;/strong>. A passive investigation is one that does not load any websites, but only looks up publicly available data on them. As such, the attacker will not be alerted that their website received additional visits, which could tip them off that an investigation is taking place. By evaluating domain and IP info, an investigator can work towards &lt;strong>generating rich technical information about the attack&lt;/strong> useful for community education, threat information sharing, discovery of associated attacker infrastructure, and for placing attacks in context of broader attack patterns.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Passive Investigation - Analyze email headers</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-5/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There is far more to emails than meets the eye. The subtopic will teach you how to &lt;strong>analyze the extensive metadata&lt;/strong> which documents an email’s origin, the servers it traveled through, information about possible spam checks, and much more. This metadata can form a crucial part of any in-depth investigation into potentially malicious emails.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Use this skill after or alongside the &lt;a href="#subtopic-4-passive-investigation-analyze-urls-hostnames-and-ip-addresses" >Triage&lt;/a> subtopic within this learning path. Some of these skills may be necessary as part of the triage process in order to decide if a message is suspicious.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Active Investigation - Analyze malicious emails</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-6/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This module will teach you how to &lt;strong>interpret and understand malicious emails&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>find the infrastructure that they link to&lt;/strong>. Whether they be pure social engineering, phishing, or malware delivery, malicious emails can be quite complex. While the immediate goal of this skill is to identify attacker infrastructure, these advanced skills of reversing complex emails are also good preparation for understanding attacker campaigns, and they are a good introduction to analyzing more complicated malware. Some of those techniques can also &lt;strong>help you analyze suspicious messages sent through other mediums, such as WhatsApp&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Active Investigation - Analyze malicious webpages</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-7/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Phishing emails are usually just the first step in an attack. Most try to get the targeted person to visit a web page with a specific attack objective. This skill module will teach you to &lt;strong>look at attacker-controlled websites to understand their actions&lt;/strong> and potentially &lt;strong>uncover further attacker-controlled infrastructure&lt;/strong> or attack vectors used in the attacks. Note that websites can be extremely complicated, with behavior ranging from simple credential-stealing impersonation pages to complex attacks against the web browser or browsing device itself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Documenting Findings</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-8/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There can be several reasons why civil society organizations do not report or share their findings. They might lack the time to do so, they might be concerned about sharing malware samples or indicators of compromise, or they might simply lack the expertise on how to responsibly document the findings of a malware investigation. This subtopic addresses the last point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prior to completing this subtopic, make sure that you’ve thoroughly read through and understood the two writeups (by Amnesty/HRW and by Bellingcat) outlined in Subtopic 7.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Response - Infrastructure takedown</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-9/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the previous sub-topics, we looked at how you can identify infrastructure that serves malicious content, be it spam, malware, or phishing. Once you have successfully done so, it’s time to warn others about it. In this subtopic, we cover &lt;strong>abuse-reporting and other safe browsing and sinkhole mechanisms&lt;/strong>. This includes contacting the infrastructure provider to report malicious infrastructure so that it can be taken down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pair this effort with broader incident response activities including threat sharing and reaching out to communities which may have also been targeted by the attacks originating from the same infrastructure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Capture-the-flag exercise</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/1/module-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>We have also designed a capture-the-flag exercise in which learners can analyze a phishing email and the infrastructure it links to. The exercise can be used as an additional practice or skill verification exercise, and can be found below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You are sitting in the bustling Press newsroom where you are working as an IT admin, sitting totally focused on your duties surrounded by glowing monitors. Your colleague Alia from Accounting rushes over with a concerned look on their face, who lets you know they forwarded an email claiming to be from PayPal which urges them to take immediate action due to suspicious account activity. The Press organization relies on PayPal for processing subscription payments. Your interest is instantly piqued as you recognize the potential of a malicious attack, and you get started on an investigation.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>