<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web Application Hardening, Forensics, and Incident Response on Infuse</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/6/</link><description>Recent content in Web Application Hardening, Forensics, and Incident Response on Infuse</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/6/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/6/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>With thanks to&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michał &amp;ldquo;czesiek&amp;rdquo; Czyżewski &lt;a href="https://czesiek.net" target="_blank" >https://czesiek.net&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yana Ghahramanyan&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Websites are critical infrastructure used by media organizations and civil society to disseminate free flow of information as well as to provide functionalities to their stakeholders. Adversaries attack these web applications for various purposes, including shutting down the free flow of information, reputational damage, access to private systems, theft of sensitive information, surveillance, and device compromise. By preparing effectively for these sorts of attacks, you can reduce their impact, or in some cases prevent them entirely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Website Hardening</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/6/module-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/6/module-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are a number of steps that can be taken to a website as a whole to make it more resilient to attack. These typically require less effort than going through the site page-by-page and can be quite impactful, so generally it’s a good idea to go through these actions first.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, the practitioner should be able to do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use development and maintenance processes that ensure that their site can be re-created if the production hosting servers are unavailable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use CDNs (content delivery networks) to protect their website from DoS attacks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use static site generators to make their site more resistant to DoS and hacking&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use configuration hardeners and WAFs to make their site more resistant to hacking&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This sub-skill covers fundamental, site-wide activities that should be performed on almost any site that wishes to be protected against attacks. While every action may not apply to every site, some apply to all sites, and all apply to some.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Website Logging for Security</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/6/module-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/6/module-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Any website that’s exposed to the internet is under constant attack. At the very least, it’s being deluged by undirected attacks by hordes of robots operated by criminal actors. More concerning are targeted attacks; even unskilled attackers, given perseverance and luck, can find vulnerabilities in a website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ideally, the website owner should be able to be aware of the threats they are facing. Site owners especially will want to know if an attacker is close to finding, or has recently found, a vulnerability in their site. Finally, if a vulnerability is exploited, site owners will want to know where the vulnerability is, and for how long it’s been exploited. Website logs can support all of these desires.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Denial of Service Incident Response</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/6/module-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/6/module-3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If a website comes under a sustained denial of service attack, it may be vital to act quickly to get the site back up and running. This subtopic describes some practices to allow site owners to recover from a DoS attack.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, the practitioner should be able to do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Determine what sort of DoS attack a website is under&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mitigate or neutralize an attack in process&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For some sites (e.g., gambling sites), even a brief DoS can be an existential threat to the site’s survival. Attackers are typically financially motivated, and will use DoS as an extortion threat. For civil society focused sites, the threat model is typically quite different. Attacks are typically controlled by political rivals (often nation-state actors or those linked to or supported by them), and fall into two categories:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hacking Incident Response</title><link>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/6/module-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/en/learning-path/6/module-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If a website is hacked, understanding the actions and methods of the attacker is vital. At the very least, the site owners need to identify how the site was initially compromised so that they can fix any vulnerabilities that enabled that. It may also be important to know what data the attackers may have accessed or modified. This subtopic describes some practices to help investigate and recover from a website hacking incident.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>