<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web Application Hardening, Forensics, and Incident Response on Infuse</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/</link><description>Recent content in Web Application Hardening, Forensics, and Incident Response on Infuse</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>ar</language><atom:link href="https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Websites are critical infrastructure used by media organizations and civil society to disseminate free flow of information as well as to provide functionalities to their stakeholders. Adversaries attack these web applications for various purposes, including shutting down the free flow of information, reputational damage, access to private systems, theft of sensitive information, surveillance, and device compromise. By preparing effectively for these sorts of attacks, you can reduce their impact, or in some cases prevent them entirely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Website Hardening</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/module-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/module-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are a number of steps that can be taken to a website as a whole to make it more resilient to attack. These typically require less effort than going through the site page-by-page and can be quite impactful, so generally it’s a good idea to go through these actions first.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, the practitioner should be able to do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use development and maintenance processes that ensure that their site can be re-created if the production hosting servers are unavailable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use CDNs (content delivery networks) to protect their website from DoS attacks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use static site generators to make their site more resistant to DoS and hacking&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use configuration hardeners and WAFs to make their site more resistant to hacking&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This sub-skill covers fundamental, site-wide activities that should be performed on almost any site that wishes to be protected against attacks. While every action may not apply to every site, some apply to all sites, and all apply to some.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Website Logging for Security</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/module-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/module-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="حالة-استخدام">حالة استخدام&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>يُعدّ أي موقع ويب على الإنترنت معرضًا لشكل مستمر للهجوم، وعلى أقل تقدير تغرق بهجمات غير موجّهة من أعداد كبيرة من روبوتات تُديرها جهات إجرامية. والأمر الأكثر إثارة للقلق هو الهجمات المستهدفة لأن حتى المهاجمين غير المهرة مع القليل من المثابرة والحظ، يمكنهم العثور على نقاط ضعف في موقع الويب.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>من الناحية المثالية، يجب أن يكون مالك موقع الويب قادرًا على إدراك التهديدات التي يواجهها، وسيرغب في معرفة ما إذا كان المهاجم قريبًا من العثور على ثغرة أمنية في موقعه أو وجدها مؤخرًا. وأخيرًا في حالة استغلال ثغرة أمنية سيرغب مالكو الموقع في معرفة مكانها ومدة استغلالها، ويمكن أن تدعم سجلات موقع الويب كل هذه الرغبات.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Denial of Service Incident Response</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/module-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/module-3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="حالة-استخدام">حالة استخدام&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>إذا تعرض موقع ويب لهجوم حجب خدمة مستمر فقد يكون من الضروري التصرف بسرعة لإعادة تشغيل الموقع وتفعيله. يصف مسار التعلّم هذا بعض الممارسات التي تسمح لمالكي الموقع التعافي من هجوم حجب الخدمة.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="الأهداف">الأهداف&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>إذا تعرض موقع ويب لهجوم حجب خدمة مستمر فقد يكون من الضروري التصرف بسرعة لإعادة تشغيل الموقع وتفعيله. يصف مسار التعلّم هذا بعض الممارسات التي تسمح لمالكي الموقع التعافي من هجوم حجب الخدمة.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>بعد استكمال هذا الموضوع الفرعي، يجب أن يكون الممارس قادرًا على القيام بما يلي:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hacking Incident Response</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/module-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/6/module-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If a website is hacked, understanding the actions and methods of the attacker is vital. At the very least, the site owners need to identify how the site was initially compromised so that they can fix any vulnerabilities that enabled that. It may also be important to know what data the attackers may have accessed or modified. This subtopic describes some practices to help investigate and recover from a website hacking incident.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>