<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web Application Security Fundamentals on Infuse</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/</link><description>Recent content in Web Application Security Fundamentals on Infuse</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>ar</language><atom:link href="https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Infrastructure Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-1/</guid><description>Use Case While this learning path focuses on web application security, web applications run on top of numerous pieces of software infrastructure. Any vulnerability in the application’s underlying infrastructure will compromise the application. Understanding some infrastructure security is therefore part of understanding application security.
When inspecting a web application either for purposes of vulnerability assessment, security monitoring, or to investigate a compromise, the practitioner must understand the underlying stack of technology which provides the necessary environment for the application to run while looking for vulnerabilities in that stack.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/introduction/</guid><description>Overview There are many ways in which adversaries could try to attack websites, including:
Denial of expression: website takedown, website defacement, denial of service Accessing sensitive data: exploiting access controls or other vulnerabilities to access information for instance in application databases, private files or systems, private inboxes or members’ areas Implanting malware ( ‘watering hole’ attacks): using access to a website to place malicious or misleading code for the purpose of achieving objectives on visitor devices Lateral movement (compromising other systems): gaining access to whole servers, cloud infrastructure, or office or home infrastructure Surveillance of visitors: obtaining information on IPs or identities of visitors to a website or users of a web application Supply chain compromise: compromising distribution services for software, building processes of software, or for component libraries of software in order to achieve malicious objectives on users of the targeted software Impersonation of websites: for purposes of phishing, muddying of reputation, and malware/spyware distribution Traffic injection (downgrading attacks): exploiting infrastructure or communications configuration weaknesses for the purpose of inserting malicious content into otherwise good traffic Web application security is a deep domain of technical knowledge with many areas of specialization.</description></item><item><title>Data Validation</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-2/</guid><description>Use Case A common class of web application vulnerabilities relates to the way the app processes data supplied by users of the site. This class of vulnerabilities is commonly used by attackers to completely take over target websites, and often can be discovered via automated techniques. Understanding the mechanisms for data validation vulnerabilities is also extremely useful for demystifying complex security topics.
Objectives After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:</description></item><item><title>Authentication</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-3/</guid><description>Use Case In any website that has user logins, it’s important that the site protects user accounts from unauthorized access, and also that the account credentials themselves are protected. This subtopic outlines the most common areas of authentication where web application flaws appear.
Objectives After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:
Understand common types of authentication vulnerabilities Understand the potential impacts of those types of vulnerabilities Understand the mechanisms by which those vulnerabilities work Understand, in broad strokes, how those vulnerabilities can be prevented Main Section Authentication is the process by which a user of a system proves that they are who they claim they are.</description></item><item><title>Authorization</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-4/</guid><description>Use Case In any website that has users with different levels of capabilities (e.g. viewers vs editors) or that holds confidential information for users, it’s important that the site protects these features and/or this data from people who don’t have permission to use these features and/or interact with this data.
Objectives After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:
Understand common types of authorization vulnerabilities Understand the potential impacts of those types of vulnerabilities Understand the mechanisms by which those vulnerabilities work Understand, in broad strokes, how those vulnerabilities can be prevented Main Section Foundation Knowledge Authorization is the process of making sure that a user of a system has permission to perform an action or create/read/edit/delete a piece of data in that system, and preventing these actions if the user doesn’t have permission.</description></item><item><title>Application Logic</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-5/</guid><description>Use Case In any interactive website that puts constraints on the types of actions that users can perform, it’s important that the site properly enforces those constraints to prevent unintended (and potentially) damaging actions by malicious users.
Objectives After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:
Understand the concept of application logic vulnerabilities Identify and understand common subclasses of application logic vulnerabilities, including: Client-side controls Lack of rate limiting/multiple submissions Rounding inconsistencies Skipping process steps Cross-site request forgery Main Section Application logic vulnerabilities (frequently called business logic vulnerabilities) are a loosely assembled class of vulnerabilities that relate to the processes that the application itself performs, as opposed to underlying vulnerabilities in the technologies that the application uses.</description></item><item><title>Interpersonal Skills for Web Application Security</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/4/module-6/</guid><description>Use Case When interacting with individuals and organizations who operate web applications, self-awareness is necessary to check the nature of the digital protector relationship, provide useful and not fear-mongering advice or services. It is critical to frame your technical work within a sound risk assessment of the reality of the web application and its users.
Objectives After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:
Self reflect on the digital protector relationship with a client within web application assessment work and reporting Simplify and filter findings and explain them in a way which makes sense to the needs and threat models of the organization and its stakeholders Maintain an awareness of the limits of your own knowledge and ability Communicate in a non fear-mongering way about vulnerabilities and weaknesses Conduct a broader risk analysis of a web application based on the political, social, economic, and technical realities which surround it.</description></item></channel></rss>