<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Análisis de Malware on Infuse</title><link>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/3/</link><description>Recent content in Análisis de Malware on Infuse</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>es</language><atom:link href="https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducción</title><link>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/3/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/3/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="descripción-general">Descripción general&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Esta ruta de aprendizaje te preparará para comenzar el camino del análisis de malware. Tenga en cuenta que esta es una de las áreas de seguridad más difíciles de dominar, pero el progreso incremental dará resultados. El objetivo general del análisis de malware es caracterizar nuevos malwares, tanto malwares nuevos como variantes de los existentes. El resultado final deseado es una caracterización de las capacidades del malware, una conjetura sobre qué actores de amenazas lo están utilizando y un conjunto de IoC (indicadores de compromiso) que permitirán a otros detectar el malware.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setting up a malware analysis environment</title><link>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/3/module-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/3/module-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before you start analyzing any malware, you need to set up a safe environment to do so. Definitionally, malware does bad things to the systems it runs on. You do not want to run it on your primary system. Additionally, you likely will want to prevent the malware from actually making connections to the threat actor’s C&amp;amp;C (command and control) servers. Both of these mean that you should set up a virtual machine to use when performing malware analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Basic file analysis</title><link>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/3/module-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/3/module-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once you have a piece of malware on your analysis VM, the next step is to figure out what’s in it. A piece of malware may use multiple files; in this case you would use the techniques in this section for each file. There are a few different ways to get an idea of what kind of file you’re dealing with. Note that some malware is tricky about this, hiding malicious content in innocuous files or making files that are several valid types at once (a classic example being the GIFAR, which is a file that is both a valid image and also a valid Java applet). Because of this, when evaluating malware files, we need to perform a deeper analysis of file types and contents. Beyond basic file extensions, we’ll examine file headers and signatures, as well as string contents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sandboxes and dynamic analysis</title><link>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/3/module-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/3/module-3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dynamic analysis is the process of running a piece of malware and observing what it does. The easiest way of doing dynamic analysis is by running a piece of software in a sandbox. A sandbox is a safe, isolated environment which opens a potentially malicious file, URL, or program and generates a huge amount of data on it. This subtopic looks at sandbox analysis, what it can and cannot do, and how to do it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Static analysis</title><link>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/3/module-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/3/module-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Static analysis is the process of disassembling a binary file in order to understand what’s inside it. It’s quite labor-intensive and requires software engineering knowledge. For this reason, most analysts will prefer to do dynamic analysis (which we focus on in Subtopic 3) instead. There are several reasons you might want to do static analysis, including when dynamic analysis isn’t yielding good results or if you do not want a potential adversary to know that you are in possession of and analyzing the file.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Creating and sharing IoCs</title><link>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/3/module-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/es/learning-path/3/module-5/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once you have analyzed a piece of malware, you can help the community (and also yourself and the rest of the world) by sharing your findings. Novel malware is reasonably rare, and once used, it tends to be re-used extensively. By sharing your findings, you can help everyone in several ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If a member of the community has been targeted by a threat actor, it’s quite possible that the threat actor is targeting other members of the community. By sharing your findings, you can help raise awareness and hopefully help digital defenders prevent or mitigate other attacks.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Analyzing a novel piece of malware is a significant achievement. You should be proud of it and also be rewarded for your efforts. By sharing your process and findings, you are more likely to be recognized for your expertise, increasing your opportunities for interesting work and collaboration in the field.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finally, by creating and sharing IoCs, you can help automatic detection of the malware in question. If makers of detection and prevention software integrate those IoCs into their databases, that renders the malware significantly less useful to threat actors and enhances the security of people all over the world.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>