<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Detecting Malware on Infuse</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/</link><description>Recent content in Detecting Malware on Infuse</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>ar</language><atom:link href="https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Interpersonal skills for detecting malware</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-1/</guid><description>Use Case Before you start analyzing any malware, you need to set up a safe environment to do so. Definitionally, malware does bad things to the systems it runs on. You do not want to run it on your primary system. Additionally, you likely will want to prevent the malware from actually making connections to the threat actor’s C&amp;amp;C (command and control) servers. Both of these mean that you should set up a virtual machine to use when performing malware analysis.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/introduction/</guid><description>Overview This learning path covers intermediate-level knowledge and skills needed to detect and identify malware either from a given sample, or actively operating on a device on a variety of device platforms. The distinction between malware and software can be very subtle, and a detailed analysis of processes and binaries to ultimately determine what is malware sometimes requires advanced-level expertise. However, the skills covered here will give you a start in detection efforts.</description></item><item><title>OPSEC prerequisites for detecting malware</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-2/</guid><description>Use Case This subtopic will allow the practitioner to ensure the security of the process and the individuals involved and implement a security policy within the computing environment the practitioner uses for malware detection.
Objectives After completing this subtopic, the practitioner should be able to ensure the confidentiality and integrity of data, which includes:
Encryption during storage and transfer Doing checksums after data acquisitions Not using devices suspected of being compromised Using air-gapped environments Ensuring security of the devices and servers used in the process Threat modeling and risk assessment Conducting backups and disk imaging Main Section Operational security for detecting malware can be divided into concerns related to specific scenarios:</description></item><item><title>How malware works and different types of malware</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-3/</guid><description>Use Case In order to start working with malware, we first need to learn about its different types. Viruses, spyware, backdoors, ransomware, and adware behave differently and are inspired by different motivations. This knowledge will help the protector to classify the type of malware detected.
Objectives After completing this subtopic, the practitioner should be able to do the following:
Differentiate between various types of malware Understand what malware can do Understand how malware infections begin Explain what indicators of compromise are Main Section In general, malware is any software that is used to do unauthorized things on a user’s computer or mobile device.</description></item><item><title>Initial steps and checks for detecting malware</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-4/</guid><description>Use Case There is a device of unknown security status and the owner wants to investigate the possibility of infection or previous compromise. Perhaps you have been handed this device physically, or perhaps you will support the client remotely. Use different off-the-shelf or built-in first party scanning tools as well as integrity checks to identify, analyze, and search for Indicators of compromise (IoC) to identify a breach, or a given suspicious malware.</description></item><item><title>Forensic methods on live Windows and macOS systems</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-5/</guid><description>Use Case Direct inspection of a device can be necessary to understand what is happening on it and to identify suspicious processes, artifacts, or traffic. Go beyond scanning tools by using methods to take a deeper look at what is happening on a device.
Objectives After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:
Understand ways of inspecting running processes and methods to sort out potentially suspicious processes Understand common persistence mechanisms and ways of checking for them Inspect network traffic for suspicious communications Main Section Forensic methods require more knowledge about the internal operations of an operating system as well as developing an instinct for what is normal vs abnormal findings.</description></item><item><title>Detecting malware through traffic analysis</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-6/</guid><description>Use Case Most malware will make some sort of network connection, be it to connect to a command and control server for further instructions or exfiltrate data from a computer. While various tactics can be used by malware to avoid being detected by antivirus scanners, in many cases an analyst with access to all network traffic from the device can spot those suspicious network connections and analyze them to look for signs of malicious activity.</description></item><item><title>Detecting malware through image acquisition (iOS, Android)</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-7/</guid><description>Use Case The first step in detecting malware on a device is to collect data from the device itself for analysis. Ideally the data will be retrieved from the device to a safe space with minimal disruption to the device itself. More advanced malware may attempt to detect forensic activity and delete itself to hamper detection and analysis.
Objectives After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:</description></item><item><title>Sample-based detection and determination</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-8/</guid><description>Use Case You have a sample of a file and need to determine if it is malicious. This may have been sent to the target by email, social media, or instant messenger, or transferred over removable media or otherwise. The file itself may be a binary, a compressed archive, a captured web page, or other file formats. The primary objective is to determine whether the file is malicious. In addition, you may be able to determine some additional useful characterizing information about the file, however for more guidance see the Malware Analysis Learning Path.</description></item><item><title>Malicious document analysis</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-9/</guid><description>Use Case While many people know to be suspicious of executable binary files, office document formats such as PDF, DOC, DOCX, XLSX, and ODT, which are used on a daily basis, are unfortunately known to be weaponized with malicious dynamic content or application exploits.
This subtopic teaches learners how they can triage and analyze potentially malicious documents.
Objectives After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:</description></item><item><title>Discovering where the malware came from</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-10/</guid><description>Use Case No malware spontaneously appears on a targeted person’s device. It always comes from somewhere. Sometimes, that somewhere is obvious: the targeted person realizes that the link they clicked on was malicious. In other cases, the infection vector may be less clear. Learning where the infection came from can be important for managing future risk. If the initial infection source was untargeted, the victim may have just been the victim of a criminal gang with no goals other than making money.</description></item><item><title>Clean-up, after-care, post-incident risk management, and information sharing</title><link>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infuse.quest/ar/learning-path/2/module-11/</guid><description>Use Case If malware or malicious traffic is found on a targeted person’s device, we need to either provide remedial after-care or targeted recommendations to allow a client to determine appropriate next steps.
Objectives After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:
Determine the appropriate clean-up method for the type of malware or indicator of compromise discovered Carry out or guide on remedial clean-up steps, including removal of persistence mechanisms, malware removal tools, reboots, factory resets Identify situations in which clean-up may not be possible and further advice or action may be necessary Document and share findings Main Section Re-enabling operating system security features Earlier in this learning path we mentioned some built-in operating system protections.</description></item></channel></rss>